ow2.org 2019-12-16

# OW2 - Privacy_Policy - OW2 Privacy Policy

At OW2 we take your right to privacy seriously. We have updated our privacy policy and drafted this new privacy notice to provide you with all information, as required by law, in a concise, transparent, intelligible and easily accessible way, in clear and plain language. This privacy policy describes the information we collect from you and how it may be stored and processed. It must be clear and easy for you to exercise the rights you are granted under data protection legislation, and for you to choose how you want to hear from us. Please let us know if anything is missing or unclear on this page.

The OW2 privacy policy was updated in view of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which came into force on the 25th of May 2018. GDPR is the short name for REGULATION (EU) 2016/679 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 27 April 2016. The regulation concerns the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data. The text of the regulation is broadly publicised and can be found in extenso on the European Commission website [here](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/eli/reg/2016/679/oj).

OW2's compliance with GDPR is a relatively light constraint.

  * We keep a simplified registry of our processing resources, as per Recital 13 which states that " _To take account of the specific situation of micro, small and medium-sized enterprises, this Regulation includes a derogation for organisations with fewer than 250 employees with regard to record-keeping._ ".
  * We do not need to designate a Data Processing Officer as per Article 37: OW2 is not a " _public authority or body_ ", we host no processing that " _require regular and systematic monitoring of data subjects_ ", nor do we process " _special categories of data pursuant to Article  9 and personal data relating to criminal convictions and offences referred to in Article 10._".
  * We must reconfirm our newsletter mailing list; as per Recital 32 " _Consent should be given by a clear affirmative act establishing a freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject's agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her, such as by a written statement, including by electronic means, or an oral statement._ ".

This notice is to comply with [Article 13](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e2254-1-1) of the GDPR regulation. It requests that we, " _at the time when personal data are obtained, provide the data subject with the following further information necessary to ensure fair and transparent processing:  _"

GDPR Disclosure| OW2  
---|---  
 _(a) the period for which the personal data will be stored, or if that is not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;_|  Personal data is stored for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it is being processed and as long as the member, user or subscriber does not require deletion whether the account is active or not.  
 _(b) the existence of the right to request from the controller access to and rectification or erasure of personal data or restriction of processing concerning the data subject or to object to processing as well as the right to data portability;_|   

Loading...

Subject:  
  
Your Email:  
  
Content:  

\- 

Yes full right is granted, please contact the OW2 Management Office at Conseil & Management, 114 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France or please send an email to the OW2 GDPR address.  
 _(c)  
\- where the processing is based on point (a) of Article 6(1) or point (a) of Article 9(2),   
\- the existence of the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal;_| \- Data is stored on the OW2 infrastructure however we use third party providers for certain of our services that may store and process some personal data; these services include: our newsletter e-mailing system, our event programme management system, our annual conference registration system and a social networks management service. We also use global platforms and social networks such as Twitter, YouTube, SideShare, Google and LinkedIn.  
-Yes full right to withdraw is granted, please contact the OW2 Management Office at Conseil & Management, 114 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France or please send an email to the OW2 GDPR address.  
 _(d) the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority;_|  Yes full right is granted. Please write to the French data protection authority: [CNIL](https://www.cnil.fr/fr/notifier-une-violation-de-donnees-personnelles).  
 _(e) whether the provision of personal data is a statutory or contractual requirement, or a requirement necessary to enter into a contract, as well as whether the data subject is obliged to provide the personal data and of the possible consequences of failure to provide such data;_|  At OW2, the data we collect is the minimum requirement to enable either the benefits of membership, usage of our services or sharing useful information. Failure to provide such data will hamper access to the benefits of membership, our services or useful information.  
 _(f) the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling, referred to in Article 22(1) and (4) and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing for the data subject._|  No such automated decision-making or profiling exists at OW2.  
  
##  **Privacy Policy Details**

###  Who we are

We are OW2, a non-profit association dedicated to the promotion of a code base of open source software and its community. Registered RNA : W784003900 with offices at Conseil & Management, 114 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France, OW2 is subjected to the laws of France and the European Union.

### From whom is personal data collected?

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. At OW2 we collect personal data from four categories of stakeholders: members, users of our services, speakers and attendees to our events, and subscribers to our mailing lists.

### The legal basis we have for processing your personal data

The legal basis for processing your personal data is your consent. OW2 uses the personal data that you provide to organize community activities, and deliver quality content and services as per your request. In certain circumstances we may otherwise process your personal data if we have a legitimate interest in doing so in the framework of OW2 operations and we are not infringing any of your rights and freedoms. In any case, OW2's legitimate operative interests do not supersede your interests.

### What personnal data may OW2 collect?

At OW2, the data we collect is the minimum requirement to enable either the benefits of membership, usage of our services or sharing useful information. Personal data include information you provide to us and information we automatically collect.

  * Information you provide to us. The different kinds of personal data collected include membership data such as name, email, address, membership category for our members, email, log-in and password for our service users, email addresses and, not always, the full name for our mailing lists subscribers, plus click statistics for our newsletter subscribers, names and emails for our event participants, and bios and photos for our speakers.
  * Information we automatically collect. We also automatically collect certain technical data that are sent to us from the computer, mobile device and/or browser through which you access our services. This kind of automatic data includes, without limitation, a unique identifier associated with your access device and/or browser (including, for example, your Internet Protocol (IP) address), characteristics about your access device and/or browser, statistics on your activities on our services, information about how you came to our services and data collected through Cookies, Pixel Tags, Local Shared Objects, Web Storage and other similar technologies.

### Why do we collect personal data?

We collect personal data for the purpose of running OW2 and its activities. Depending on the category of stakeholders, this includes making possible the execution of the membership contract, enabling you to securely log in our services, and sharing information across the community and its ecosystem. If you choose not to provide us with your personal information, you may hamper access to the benefits of membership, our services and useful information.

### Where is the data being stored?

This data is stored on the OW2 infrastructure for all services except for few external online services such as pour newsletter e-mailing system, our event programme management system and our annual conference registration system.

### Who has access to the data?

Access to personal data is granted to no one except OW2 personnel for management and operation purposes.

### For how long the data will be kept?

Personal data is stored for as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it is being processed and as long as the member, user, subscriber, speaker or otherwise does not require deletion.

### Is the data being transferred?

We do not rent or sell your personal identifiable information to third parties. However we use third party providers for certain of our services that may store and process some personal data. These services include: our newsletter e-mailing system, our event programme management system, our annual conference registration system and a social networks management service. We also use global platforms and social networks such as Twitter, YouTube, SideShare, Google and LinkedIn.

### Will your personal data be transferred to a recipient outside the EU?

OW2 uses third party online applications and services which may be provided by compute resources located outside of the EU and which may need to process personal data. We use trusworthy third party applications and services and trust that any personal identifiable information you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

### Is there any automated decision-making based on personal data?

No.

### Changes to this privacy notice

This privacy notice may change from time to time. For example, we may update this notice to reflect any relevant changes to legislation and regulation, to the processing resources we use and to our policy. Please visit this section of the website periodically to keep up-to-date with the changes in our privacy policy.

### Do I have a right to a copy of my personal data stored by OW2?

Yes. Please contact the OW2 Management Office at Conseil & Management, 114 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France or please send an email to the OW2 GDPR address. 

You also have all other basic rights in the field of data protection such as the right to lodge a complaint with a [Data Protection Authority (DPA)](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm) and the right to withdraw consent at any time.

### Who can you contact with regard to this privacy policy?

The OW2 Management Office (no Data Protection Officer required) is in charge of keeping our privacy policy and GDPR process up to date. If you have any question regarding this privacy notice, please contact the OW2 Management Office at Conseil & Management, 114 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France or please send an email to the OW2 GDPR address.

##  **Use of Cookies**

###  Why we use cookies

We use cookies to facilitate your navigation on our web sites. We do not use cookies for marketing purposes.  
Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. They are also useful to provide you with more relevant information.

### The cookies we use

We keep our use of cookies to the strict minimum. The table below explains the cookies we are using and why :

Cookie type| Purpose  
---|---  
XWiki| These are technical cookies used to improve your browsing experience on our websites. For example, they maintain your session when you login, automatically provide your user name in the login field, remember your browsing preference settings, etc.  
Google Analytics| These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. [Overview of privacy at Google.](https://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html)  
Third-party apps| We use third-party application which may collect cookies. For example, we embed videos from our official OW2 channel using YouTube’s privacy-enhanced mode. This mode may set cookies on your computer once you click on the YouTube video player, but YouTube will not store personally-identifiable cookie information for playbacks of embedded videos using the privacy-enhanced mode.  
Social networks| Cookies from social networks such as LinkedIn, Twitter and SlideShare are used to enable you to share pages and content that you find interesting on our Websites through third party social networking and other websites. These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes too.  

### What happens if the use of cookies is declined?

You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies. The website will still work and you will be able to get the information you need from the site. But as we develop how the site works and offer more sophisticated services through it this will most likely rely on cookies. If you decline cookies then we will not be able to count your site usage in the statistics that we gather about use of the site. We use Google Analytics to count the number of people who use the site and to analyse how they use it. If you decline cookies then your site usage won't be counted and measured in this way so we won't be able to take your actions into account when analysing data and seeking to improve our service based on that analysis.

##  **Disclaimer**

Privacy protection and compliance with the GDPR constitute a sensitive endeavour. As in everything we do at OW2 it has to be a co-production between OW2 and its members and account owners in their use of OW2's services. We share as much information and resources as we can so as to facilitate cooperation between OW2 and our members and account owners in their use of our services. It may be that our web sites and forms may need fine-tuning to be fully GDPR-compliant, please feel free to contact us should you come across any web page where required GDPR-related information or notice is missing.
